Christophe Foyer

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com France: (+33) 6 78 56 99 03 • United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 French and US citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

Summary:

Mechanical Engineering graduate with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, and aerospace engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

• CAD, FEA and CFD

• Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)

Embedded systems

• Linux Server Management and Software Development

Education:

RWTH Aachen

Washington University in Saint Louis

Saint Louis, United States Aug 2014 – Dec 2017

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

3.14/4.00 GPA

• Dean's List (Fall 2014, Fall 2017)

Aachen, Germany

Study Abroad; 'Renewable Energy Technology' | 'Mechatronics and Product Innovation'

Jun 2017 – Jul 2017

School for International Training

Reykjavik, Iceland Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

Study abroad in Renewable Energy Engineering and Resource Economics

Caen, France

Lycée Sainte Marie Série S (Science track)

Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

• French Baccalauréat: "Mention Bien" (with honors)

Relevant Experience:

Tata Steel Europe

IJmuiden, Netherlands

Mechanical Engineering Intern

 $Apr\ 2018-July\ 2018$

- Successfully built and implemented a real-time thermal simulation in Python reducing estimation error by 82.4%
- Estimating steel slab temperature within 21 degrees leading to potential savings of one million euros per year
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

Treasurer

Aug 2016 – May 2017

- Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition (1st in the US Midwest)
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to the competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

American Society of Mechanical Engineers

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Event Planner

Sep 2016 – May 2017

- Researched and presented reasons to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus for \$45,000; secured a date for his visit
- Advised ASME members with ongoing projects on manufacturing and component selection.

Skills and Abilities:

CAD / FEA / CFD: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, AutoCAD, XFLR5

Programming Languages: Python, Matlab, Simulink, SQL, Arduino C (C/C++), HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication: 3D-Printing (FDM), Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite Manufacturing

Software: Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word), git, Windows, Linux

Languages: Bilingual French / English; Basic German and Icelandic

Academic Projects:

Senior Design Project – Low-Cost CPV

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%

Independent Projects:

Printable Folding Tricopter

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing:

- Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Nettfab to be 3D-printed
- Designed to minimize weight and exterior volume while maximizing payload space

Motor Test Stand Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U Design/Build/Fly:

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new Windows installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

Electric Longboard Oct 2016 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard:

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminum and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations

Naïve Bayes Classifier

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016

Coding of a Naïve Bayes Classifier for financial forecasting using machine learning:

- Coded a Bayesian classifier from scratch in python and tested it against other bayes classifiers on test datasets
- Achieved comparable performance while supporting missing datapoints

IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation

Jan 2015 – May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media center system:

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python 2.7 on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (added support for Windows and OSX)
- Control over house appliances and interfacing with Open Source Media Center

Robotics Test Platform Dec 2013 – Jan 2015

Design, coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing:

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over IP
- Experiments in visual odometry using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

Volunteering and Work Experience:

ICC
Volunteer

Ishinomaki, Japan
May 2014

Construction of wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.

Domaine du Vivier

Le Mesnil Mauger, France Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

Seasonal farm hand

- Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work
- Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer